(September 7, 1589 AD)
（公元1589年9月7日）
Mr. Lu has come forward several times
卢先生多次出面
Is the dregs ready?
渣子准备好了吗？
yes it is
是的
Mr. Lu
先生。太阳
I'll take you to your room
我带你去你的房间
Mom, my dad got drunk again
妈妈，爸爸又喝醉了
ping
平
Ignore your father
无视你的父亲
Let's go and eat okay?
我们去吃饭好吗？
ping
平
but you are
但你是
It's getting dark
天快黑了
Don't read books outside anymore
别再在外面看书了
Yes, mom
好的，妈妈
Xiao Bao
Xiao Bao
Found an interesting place
发现一个有趣的地方
in our home
在我们家
Any interesting place?
有什么有趣的地方吗？
Today, I couldn't find Lu Che
今天找不到陆澈了
I believed
我相信
Maybe he went fishing with Mr. Zhong again
也许他又和钟先生一起去钓鱼了
So, I went to Mr. Zhong's courtyard
于是，我就去了钟先生的院子里
Mr. Chung was not there
钟先生不在
The patio door was stuck
露台门被卡住了
After that, out of boredom
之后，出于无聊
The tree was planted in the adjacent yard
这棵树种 在邻近的院子里
And I entered his yard
我走进了他的院子
Why did you get into his art?
为什么你会喜欢上他的艺术？
I always find this curiosity very strange
我总觉得这种好奇心很奇怪
maybe
或许
Because he ran out
因为他跑出去了
I found a secret in the yard
我在院子里发现了一个秘密
Head?
头？
What secret?
什么秘密？
Found it in the yard
在院子里发现的
There is a well
有一口井
a well?
一口井？
this is very strange
这很奇怪
Why is there a well?
为什么会有一口井？
It's a dry well
这是一口干井
What?
什么？
This is even strange
这更奇怪了
How can there be dry wells?
怎么会有干井呢？
in this world?
在这世上？
If you act like this, I won't tell you anymore
如果你再这样， 我就不告诉你了
I see
我懂了
Go
去
There is a rope in the well
井里有一根绳子
I followed him down
我跟着他下来
Certainly enough
当然够了
Found a secret room
发现了一个秘密房间
At the bottom of the well
在井底
Secret room?
密室？
What's inside?
里面是什么？
nothing
没有什么
Let's go
我们走吧
It was black inside and I couldn't see anything
里面一片漆黑 ，什么也看不见
I didn't bring a torch
我没带火炬
but
但
The secret room is impressive enough
密室够震撼
I hear
我听到
Rich families have this kind of place
有钱人家都有这样的地方
Used to obliterate money
用来抹掉金钱
I heard about that too
我也听说过
So how exactly did you leave the yard?
那么你到底是怎么离开院子的呢？
There are trees in the courtyard of the supervising side
监理方院内有树
Xiaobao
小宝
Why don't you stay here today?
今天你为什么不留在这里？
When Mr. Zhong is sleeping tonight
今晚钟先生睡觉的时候
We can go
我们可以去
Explore together with Lu Che
与陆彻一起探索
Is it delicious?
好吃吗？
How is your cooking skill?
你的厨艺怎么样？
Tasty
可口
But it's salty
不过是咸的
This is not usually the case
通常情况并非如此
It's salty today
今天有点咸
I originally wanted to bring you soup
本来想给你送汤的
But I got my hands full
但我忙得不可开交
I'll get you some water
我给你拿点水
No thank you
不，谢谢
I will do it myself
我自己做
there is no place
没有地方了
Lu Che
陆彻
Did you serve your teacher well?
你有好好侍奉老师吗？
Mr. Lu
先生。太阳
Very sleepy?
很困吗？
Are you tired of climbing?
你爬累了吗？
It's very salty
很咸
How much salt is used in cooking?
做饭时用了多少盐？
I'll find some water
我去找点水
The water stone is empty
水石已空
Each one must be killed with a single stab
每个人都必须一刺杀死
Don't make noise
不要发出噪音
Why take unnecessary actions?
为什么要采取不必要的行动？
We'll start the fire anyway
无论如何我们都会生火
What if I wake them up now?
如果我现在叫醒他们怎么办？
What if they wake up when the fire is lit?
如果他们在火被点燃时醒来怎么办？
Will you be responsible then?
到时候你会负责吗？
I...
我...
Where did Mr. Lu learn this method?
陆先生这个方法是从哪里学来的？
Tonight, we'll all have blood on our hands
今晚，我们手上都会沾满鲜血
We'll be in the same boat
我们将在同一条船上
I will kill Luo Jinchen
我要杀了洛锦辰
Liu Shiqi will kill his wife and daughter
刘士奇将杀妻 女
Chen Wang
Chen Wang
I will kill you if you are with me
如果你和我在一起我会杀了你
Let's go
我们走吧
Mr. Lu
先生。太阳
Why is your house so quiet?
你家怎么这么安静？
Kuihua Tower is noisy at this time
奎华楼此时喧闹
A good family is quiet?
好家庭就安静吗？
Smoke
抽烟
Where is the smoke?
烟在哪里？
He's on fire
他火了
Mr. Lu
先生。太阳
Xiao Bao
Xiao Bao
Get out of here
离开这里
horse
马
There's a side door to the stables
马厩有一扇侧门
Go that way
走那条路
Who grabbed the straws here?
谁抓住了这里的救命稻草？
Mr. Lu
先生。太阳
Where should we go?
我们应该去哪里？
To Bir Al-Jaf
前往比尔贾夫
Mr. Chung's yard is nearby
钟先生的院子就在附近
Let's hide there
我们躲在那里吧
where?
在哪里？
there
那里
Go
去
Mr. Lu
先生。太阳
How deep is this well?
这口井有多深？
It is very deep
很深
When I came during the day
我白天来的时候
There was a rope here
这里有一根绳子
Where is the rope?
绳子在哪里？
pregnancy
怀孕
ping
平
my dad and mom
我爸爸和妈妈
Mr. Lu
先生。太阳
no
不
I have to find ping
我必须找到 ping
I must find her
我必须找到她
Mr. Lu
先生。太阳
ping
平
Let's avoid the fire first
我们首先要避免火灾
They must all be sold out
一定都卖完了
Its people?
它的人？
Yes
是的
permission
允许
All sold out
全部售完
Let's jump
我们跳吧
We ran out
我们跑完了
jumps?
跳跃？
no
不
Without the cord
不带电源线
We can't get out first
我们无法先出去
I might find it in stability
我可能会发现它稳定
You are waiting here
你在这里等
I will look for it
我会寻找它
Put this
把这个
Breathe less smoke
少吸点烟
I didn't start a fire in the back garden
我没有在后花园生火
We can leave there later
我们可以稍后离开那里
I have nothing to take
我没有什么可带走的
What are we doing here?
我们在这里做什么？
I have something I need to take
我有东西需要拿走
What is it?
它是什么？
there
那里
I want to come back
我想回来
Why?
为什么？
Understood
明白了
I discovered...
我发现...
I discovered my gold
我发现了我的黄金
You want gold
你想要黄金
The gold that Lu Yuanbao gave me
陆元宝给我的金子
What?
什么？
You lost your mind
你失去了理智
I have gold
我有金子
Good
好的
Lu Yuanbao didn't tell you to kill me, right?
陆元宝没有让你 杀我吧？
Yes, he did that
是的，他这么做了
You're fantasizing about me, aren't you?
你正在对我产生幻想，不是吗？
no
不
You wanted me to be your son, didn't you?
你希望我 成为你的儿子，不是吗？
Yes
是的
you are crazy
你疯了
I don't need a father
我不需要父亲
I won't let you control me anymore
我不会再让你控制我了
Why is this happening?
为什么会发生这种情况？
Why?
为什么？
Xiao Bo
Xiao Bo
He's on fire
他火了
What are you standing there for?
你站在那里干嘛？
Go get someone to put out the fire!
去找人来救火吧！
Go
去
shoot!
射击！
I'll go get it
我去拿
Captain Lang
郎队长
Look at them
看他们
that they...
他们...
What are you doing here?
你在这里做什么？
You can hide
你可以隐藏
Or pretend to start a fire
或者假装生火
How do you watch that?
你怎么看？
Yes
是的
That was my lack of destiny
那是我命运的缺失
Your inability?
你的无能？
Another life was lost because of your lack of concern
又一个生命因为你的不关心而失去
That night watchman is a good guy
那个守夜人是个好人
He is a good person
他是一个好人
Many good people died today
今天死了很多好人
The number of bodies is in line with the number of people
尸体数量 与人数一致
Is there anyone else?
还有其他人吗？
Who is as tall as you?
谁和你一样高？
Even with you?
甚至和你在一起？
What happened?
发生了什么？
I did not find Le Bot's body in his room
我在勒博特的房间里没有找到他的尸体
But I found one somewhere else
但我在其他地方找到了一个
Chen Wang...
Chen Wang...
Can you show me the body?
你能给我看看尸体吗？
What interest?
什么兴趣？
It's burned out now
现在已经烧毁了
However, I have to see it
但是，我必须看到它
He must die
他必须死
= Rippy Town = = Episode 12 =
= Rippy Town = = 第 12 集 =
(Three days after the fire in 1589 AH)
（伊斯兰教历 1589 年火灾发生后三天）
Lu Che
陆彻
I just went through a big incident like this
我刚刚经历了 这样的大事件
what are you doing here?
你在这里做什么？
Mr. Chow
周先生
before
前
Mr. Lu gave me a receipt
卢先生给了我一张收据
He asked me to show it to you
他让我给你看
But before this
但在此之前
The accident happened
事故发生了
Which Mr. Lu?
哪个陆先生？
You'll know as soon as you see it
你一看到就知道了
Answer him
回答他
Mr. Lu ordered me
陆先生命令我
It just allows you to see that
它只是让你看到
Leave us alone
别管我们了
Please
请
What do you mean by this?
你这是什么意思？
please forgive me
请原谅我
These are instructions from Mr. Lu
这是卢先生的指示
You have to read it that way
你必须这样读
This is Lu Yuanbao's handwriting
这是陆元宝的笔迹
Indeed, he wrote it
确实是他写的
Lu Che is sincere
陆澈是真心的
and Makres
和马克雷斯
I feel sorry for losing his parents so early
我 为这么早失去父母感到难过
He's a worker
他是一名工人
But he is really like my son
但他真的很像我的儿子
Therefore, I will give him my shares in Hongchun Textile Restaurant
所以我就把我 宏春纺织餐厅的股份给他
To reward his loyalty
为了奖励他的忠诚
Mr. Chow
周先生
I am just a humble servant
我只是一个卑微的仆人
I didn't dare cross it
我不敢跨过它
But since Mr. Lu had this will
但既然陆先生有这个意愿
I don't dare contradict that
我不敢反驳
Amol
阿莫尔
We can cooperate well in the future
我们以后可以很好地合作
how dare you
你怎么敢
I made a will to seize the inheritance
我立下 遗嘱夺取遗产
I will hand you over
我会把你交给你
Oh, my God!
我的天啊！
What a simple maid!
多么简单的女仆啊！
It's dry
天气干燥了
how dare you
你怎么敢
Lu Jin accuses Xin of bedding and seizing the inheritance
路晋指责辛铺垫 并夺取遗产
Moreover, the entire Lu family had died
而且，陆家全家都死了
You don't have any evidence
你没有任何证据
It must be slander
一定是诽谤
Somebody!
有人！
His anger 40 times
他的愤怒40次
I'm low key
我很低调
If my teacher is killed
如果我的老师被杀了
It would be disrespectful
这将是不尊重的
Regardless of right or wrong
不论对与错
It will overwhelm me first
它首先会让我不知所措
Multiplication requires skills
乘法需要技巧
Serious right-wingers cannot right-wing
严肃的右翼分子不能右翼
Without years of practice
没有多年的实践
What do they practice?
他们练习什么？
Stretch on people forcefully
用力拉伸人
But it doesn't hurt
但这并不痛
It only costs money
只需要钱
This is a good way to make money
这是一个赚钱的好方法
He seems to be in the right days
他似乎正处于正确的日子
Even multiplication under the command of money
甚至在金钱的指挥下倍增
Don't worry about coverage
不用担心覆盖范围
I have a plan
我有个计划
Thank you for your help
感谢您的帮助
Once you finish it
一旦你完成它
I will recover the sinyang for you
我会为你恢复神阳
Sir, please
先生，请
Even though I'm being beaten, I have to complain
即使被打，我也得抱怨
Kill Mr. Lu
杀死先生 太阳
prattle
喋喋不休
His anger 60 times
他的愤怒60次
Even if I get beaten to death I have to seek justice for Mr. Lu
就算被打死也要 为陆先生讨回公道
Lu Yuanbao had been dead for about half a year
陆元宝已经死了 半年了
Why would you wait until after Luo Jinxin's family was dead to report it?
为什么要等到洛锦心的家人 死了之后才去报告？
When he was alive
当他还活着的时候
How dare I complain
我怎么敢抱怨
How can I fight against it?
我该如何对抗它？
Stop arguing here
别在这里争论了
Wash it 80 times
洗80次
my lord
我的主
I have an Imperial Scholar to testify
我有翰林学士作证
to stop
停止
Who is he?
他是谁？
It's Zhao Yuren
It's Zhao Yuren
Go ahead if you want to transfer us there
如果您想送我们去那里，请尽管
But there is something
但有件事
You don't want Yamin to know
你不想让亚敏知道
Mr. Chow
周先生
Your monetary unit is 5,000 taels of silver
您的货币单位是5000两白银
Not burned in fire
没有在火中被烧毁
What does the International Organization for Migration say?
国际移民组织怎么说？
I don't know
我不知道
And also
并且
The textile stuffing accountant should have been missing
纺织填料会计师 应该失踪了
Has the ledger also disappeared?
账本也消失了吗？
But I happen to know where she is
但我碰巧知道她在哪里
Did you even nominate an accountant?
你甚至提名了一名会计师吗？
But don't forget your identity
但不要忘记你的身份
You're just a maid
你只是一个女仆
If the harsh punishment is carried out...
如果实施严厉的惩罚……
you are right
你是对的
If you take me to Yemen
如果你带我去也门
You will win the case
你会赢得官司
I know that
我知道
So why are you here?
那么你为什么在这里？
I know what will happen
我知道会发生什么
The district judge knows better
地区法官 更了解
permission
允许
Trust, and international organization
信任和国际组织
Narratives and witnesses
叙述和目击者
Real or fake
真或假
The district judge will know
地方法官会知道的
I've heard the current district judge
我听说现任地区法官
He knows better about money
他对金钱更了解
If you are a district judge
如果您是地区法官
I think for sure
我想肯定的是
Mr. Zhao's case is not simple
赵先生的案子并不简单
The key is to get the benefits
关键是要得到好处
There has to be an amount, right?
总得有个数额吧？
Let me help you calculate
我帮你算一下
5000 taels of silver
白银5000两
And half Hongchun textile mill
和半红春纺织厂
If you are the county governor
如果你是县长
I would like to order from you for at least 40,000 taels of silver
我想向你订购 至少四万两白银
This is out of friendship for you
这是出于对你的友谊
You are of no use at all in prison
你在监狱里一点用处也没有
Not to mention you have to spend a lot of money
更不用说 还得花很多钱
I've got an idea
我有一个主意
To save you from this trouble
为了让你摆脱这个麻烦
My name is your price
我的名字就是你的价格
I don't need your money
我不需要你的钱
Lu Che
陆彻
What on earth are you doing?
你到底在做什么？
Early tomorrow
明天早些时候
I will go to Yemen to file a lawsuit
我要去也门提起诉讼
against me?
反对我？
I'll settle for Lu Genshin
我就选陆原真
To kill his brother Lu Yuanbao
杀兄卢元宝
To seize family property
夺取家庭财产
What?
什么？
So, I hope you can be a witness
所以，我希望 你能成为见证者
To support justice for Mr. Lu Yuanbao
为卢元宝先生伸张正义
You have physical evidence
你有物证
From Mr. Lu
来自卢先生
Hope you can submit it
希望您能提交
If you can be a witness you will save a large amount of money
如果你能成为证人， 你会节省一大笔钱
Mr. Chow
周先生
Isn't this
这不是吗
Good deal?
好交易吗？
my lord
我的主
Lu Yuanbao and I were friends
我和陆元宝是朋友
Unfortunately
很遗憾
He died too early
他死得太早了
Mr. Chow
周先生
According to Lu Che, Lu Yuanbao once told you
According to Lu Che, Lu Yuanbao once told you
That his brother wanted to kill him
他的兄弟想杀他
During his illness, I visited him
他生病期间我去看望了他
He mentioned that
他提到
What did you say?
你说什么？
I thought he was delusional because of his illness
我以为他是因为生病而产生了妄想
in addition to
此外
That was his family matter
那是他的家庭问题
As an outsider, it is inappropriate
作为一个局外人，这是不合适的
For me to intervene
让我介入
But I told
但我告诉
Their birth, Lu Zhong
他们的诞生，陆中
If only I could say anything about it
如果我能对此说点什么就好了
I asked them to take good care of Mr. Lu
我让他们好好照顾陆先生
And calm down Mr. Lu
让陆先生冷静一下
Lu Che
陆彻
What Mr. Zhao said makes sense
赵先生说的有道理
It may be possible
或许有可能
That Mr. Lu had a deception
说陆先生有诈骗行为
my lord
我的主
Captain Ling
凌队长
sir
先生
When Lu Yuanbao died
When Lu Yuanbao died
Everyone thought he died of illness
大家都以为他病死了
So they buried him immediately
于是他们立即把他埋葬了
So, you mean...
那么，你的意思是...
Exhuming the body
挖掘尸体
Coroner
验尸官
What are the results?
结果如何？
my lord
我的主
She first tested for poison with a silver needle
她先用银针试毒
She stuck the needle down my throat
她把针扎进我的喉咙
And the chest and abdomen
还有胸部和腹部
The tip of the needle has become black
针尖变黑了
Please take a look
请看一下
Then I used the bone steam method
然后我用了骨蒸法
All the bones were black
所有的骨头都是黑色的
The victim died from the poison
受害人中毒身亡
Lu Che
陆彻
As I said
就像我说的
Mr. Lu was actually poisoned to death by his younger brother
陆先生其实是 被弟弟毒死的
But his brother's family was already dead
但他哥哥的家人 已经死了
Revenge came very quickly
复仇来得很快
The killer died
凶手死了
You...
你...
my lord
我的主
Mr. Zhao is here to see you
赵先生来看你了
He knows something relevant to the case
他知道一些与案件相关的事情
Bring it
带上它
Yes
是的
my lord
我的主
Why did you come back?
你为什么回来？
On my way back home
在我回家的路上
I remembered something strange
我想起了一些奇怪的事情
Something strange?
奇怪的东西？
What is it?
它是什么？
Here's the thing
事情是这样的
Before Mr. Lu's death
卢先生去世前
He had whipped something into my pawn shop
他把东西塞进我的当铺
Here he is
他在这里
Yes
是的
Mr. Lu asked me to buy that
卢先生让我买那个
I almost forgot about it
我差点忘了这件事
I was angry at the time
我当时很生气
I was curious why he sells things
我很好奇他为什么卖东西
It was worth only 2000 copper coins
只值2000铜币
A shopkeeper also found it strange
店主也觉得奇怪
And he told me that
他告诉我
I just thought Lu Yuanbao was lost due to illness
我只是以为 陆元宝是因为病走丢了
She didn't take it seriously
她没有认真对待
What did Lu Yuanbao do?
陆元宝做了什么？
I don't know
我不知道
Mr. Chow
周先生
In your workshop
在你的车间里
Even an unknown item could be worth 2,000 copper coins
即使是不知名的物品 也能值两千铜币
I think your pawn shop won't last long
我认为你的当铺不会长久
I'm serious, sir
我是认真的，先生
When the item has been worn
当该物品已被磨损时
It was sealed
被封印了
Mr. Lu himself stamped it
卢先生亲自盖章
He specifically ordered me
他特意吩咐我
Sold by Mr. Chow's workshop
周先生工场出售
He claimed that they were his pawns
他声称他们是他的棋子
It could be worth 2000 copper coins without being detected
不被发现的情况下价值2000铜币
So I don't know what's inside it
所以我不知道里面有什么
permission
允许
Let's open the door
让我们打开门
Yes sir
是的先生
my lord
我的主
There are two rings on it
上面有两个圆环
One stamp from the store
一张商店印章
History is on it
历史就在上面
Before the time Lu Yuanbao died
陆元宝去世前
The other seal must be placed
必须放置另一个密封件
By Liu Yuanbao himself
刘元宝本人
The dates on the seals are the same
印章上的日期是一样的
So the seal has already been closed
所以封印已经关闭了
By Lu Yuanbao
By Lu Yuanbao
Before his death
在他去世前
Yes sir
是的先生
open it
打开它
I am Lu Yuanbao
I am Lu Yuanbao
From Mo County
从莫县出发
In 1568 AD
公元1568年
I came to Du County for work
我来杜县工作
I'll give it to Mr. Zhao
我给赵先生
Justice exists
正义存在
The law of karma will prevail
业力法则将占上风
I hope you can do me justice
我希望你能公正地对待我
And bring my stupid brother to justice
把我愚蠢的兄弟 绳之以法
Before Lu Yuanbao
Before Lu Yuanbao
Is this his handwriting?
这是他的笔迹吗？
my lord
我的主
I have a crush on him
我迷恋他
You can check his handwriting
你可以检查他的笔迹
Sign and seal
签字盖章
It's matching
是相配的
Compare the handwriting on this fan
比较一下这把扇子上的字迹
Handwriting on this
在此手写
Lacks power
缺乏动力
It was definitely written by a sick person
这绝对是一个病人写的
This will is real
这个意志是真实的
Lu Yuanbao is wise
Lu Yuanbao is wise
i can't believe
我不敢相信
Keep his will in store
保留他的意愿
This issue is already very clear
这个问题已经很明确了
Physical evidence and witnesses
物证和证人
And Mr. Chow
还有周先生
A highly respected Imperial scholar can testify
一位德高望重的帝国学者 可以作证
but
但
This case looks amazing
这个案例看起来很神奇
It's like a story
这就像一个故事
This is really unreasonable
这实在是不合理
He has ups and downs, poignant
他有坎坷，也有凄美
A dedicated servant of justice to his teacher
为老师尽心尽责的正义仆人
A generous master gave his family wealth
一位慷慨的主人 给了他的家庭财富
The law of karma prevails
业力法则盛行
In addition, we have a wise judge
此外，我们还有一位明智的法官
Sir, you are wise
先生，你很聪明
Sir, you persevere
先生，你坚持
The Lu family has a lot of property
陆家有很多财产
Transportation will be very troublesome
交通会很麻烦
Some may refuse to accept it
有些人可能会拒绝接受
Which leads to disputes
从而引发纠纷
my lord
我的主
We will depend on you in this matter
在这件事上我们将依赖你
Lu Che
陆彻
What is your opinion
你有什么意见
my lord
我的主
I do not know much
我不太了解
But I know one thing
但我知道一件事
What is it?
它是什么？
Be grateful
心怀感激
What?
什么？
Are we leaving?
我们要走了吗？
Why?
为什么？
My teacher's family was dead
我老师的家人都死了
But the maid gained a fortune
但女仆却发财了
This story will spread throughout DOE County
这个故事将传遍 整个 DOE 县
Mr. Lu
先生。太阳
Just let it be
随它去吧
It's not a big deal
没什么大不了的
But if everyone in this city
但如果这个城市的每个人
He is jealous of you
他嫉妒你
It would be a serious matter
这将是一个严重的问题
After all, we have a lot of secrets
毕竟我们有很多秘密
Secrets may be divulged
秘密可能会泄露
Three years
三年
We'll be leaving for three years
我们将离开三年
So we will come back with new identities
所以我们会带着新的身份回来
Mr. Lu
先生。太阳
I can agree to anything
我可以同意任何事情
Except this
除了这个
First, after all these years
首先，这么多年之后
I finally got my head together and lived a good life
我终于清醒过来， 过上了美好的生活
Do you want me to change my name?
你想让我改名字吗？
I can't do that
我不能那样做
Secondly, you know
其次，你知道
My mother's health is not good
我妈妈的身体不好
I can't leave her alone
我不能丢下她一个人
permission
允许
Just go
去吧
And I will stay
我会留下来
I gave you the house
我把房子给你了
Can't you hire some people to take care of your mother?
你就不能雇一些人 来照顾你妈妈吗？
Three years
三年
I don't even know if my mother will be able to live after three years
我什至不知道 三年后我妈妈还能不能活下去
I can't miss it one last time
我不能错过 最后一次
Chen Wang
Chen Wang
Did you gamble again a few days ago?
前几天你又赌博了吗？
I have spend a lot of money
我花了很多钱
Isn't this suspicious?
这不是很可疑吗？
you go
你去
close your mouth
闭上你的嘴
How much I spend is my business
花多少钱是我的事
Don't interfere with this
不要干涉这个
It doesn't matter, I spent my own money
没关系，我花的是我自己的钱
Who can object?
谁可以反对？
Furthermore it
此外它
Since the fire
自从火灾发生以来
We have been here for two months
我们已经在这里两个月了
Two months
两个月
I told them
我告诉了他们
Over the past two months
过去两个月
I was lucky
我很幸运
I won some big packages in the county city
我在县城赢了一些大包裹
Who might be suspicious?
谁可能会怀疑？
You are silly
你好傻
Sit
坐
Calm down, we are brothers
冷静点，我们是兄弟
Drink
喝
You two drink
你们两个喝
I'll check with my mom
我会和我妈妈确认一下
Come back early
早点回来
We haven't finished yet
我们还没有完成
(in 1609 AH)
（伊斯兰历 1609 年）
If this is true
如果这是真的
Judge Wei is the killer
魏法官就是凶手
He came back for revenge
他回来报仇
Given this
鉴于这种
We only have two paths to take
我们只有两条路可走
First, we changed our names again and fled somewhere else
首先，我们再次改名 逃往其他地方
secondly...
第二...
Kill him
杀了他
Just based on an observation from a fortune teller?
仅仅基于 算命师的观察？
What if he's lying?
如果他说谎怎么办？
Why would he lie?
他为什么要说谎？
How did he know about Lu Bu?
他是怎么知道吕布的？
makes sense
说得通
A new local judge must meet the local squid
新的当地法官 必须会见当地的鱿鱼
To make communications
进行沟通
Judge Wei has been here for several months
魏法官来了 好几个月了
But I haven't met him
但我还没见过他
It's weird
有点奇怪
This is just weird
这很奇怪
But I saw him
但我看到了他
Even though it's been 20 years
尽管已经过去了20年
I simply cannot believe it
我简直不敢相信
It's yours
是你的
It's not that you can't believe it
并不是你不相信
You're hoping for luck
你希望有好运
You don't need to panic
你无需惊慌
On the surface he still couldn't do anything to us
表面上 他还是拿我们没办法
in the dark
在黑暗中
We have a lot of people here
我们这里有很多人
He cannot be close to us
他无法靠近我们
Now, both sides
现在，双方
In trouble
麻烦
What is there to worry about?
有什么可担心的呢？
All the time
每时每刻
Our difficulty lies in the fact that the killer is hiding
我们的困难在于 凶手躲藏起来
We do not know who is being killed
我们不知道谁被杀
It doesn't matter if it's true or false
不管是真是假
Is it that difficult to kill an official?
杀一个官员有那么难吗？
Liu Shiqi
Liu Shiqi
Kill anyone with one finger
用一根手指杀死任何人
Don't mention Liu Shiqi again
别再提 刘士奇了
I can't even protect Zhang Jie
我连张杰都保护不了
Just let me leave it to me
就让我把它留给我吧
I am waiting
我在等待
The killer is very cunning
凶手非常狡猾
If you fail
如果你失败了
It would be harder to kill him again
想要再杀他就更难了
do not you trust me?
难道你不相信我？
Liu Shiqi
Liu Shiqi
In an assassination
在一次暗杀中
Do you rely solely on martial arts?
难道只靠武术吗？
Careful planning and flexibility are also important
仔细的计划 和灵活性也很重要
In the two days
这两天里
All Yamin visitors can't stop you
所有亚敏访客都无法阻止你
Except for one man
除了一个男人
That man's name is Liuyi San
那个人的名字叫六一三
he is strong
他很强
Let's get rid of it first
让我们先摆脱它
Mr. Shaw ran away
肖先生逃跑了
What?
什么？
He left with more than 100 guards
他带着100多名侍卫离开
Through the eastern gate
穿过东门
Levi San
列维·桑
Judge Wei orders you to follow them immediately
魏法官命令你 立即跟随他们
To know where they stop
知道他们停在哪里
Mail the news here all the way
一路邮寄新闻到这里
Yes
是的
Mr. Xie plans to play tricks
谢先生打算耍花招
He is pretending and will move slowly
他在假装并且会慢慢移动
(City gate opens) Take this with you
（城门打开） 带着这个
In case of breaking news
如果发生突发新闻
If the gate is about to close
如果大门即将关闭
This will work
这会起作用
Help yourself
帮助自己
Yes
是的
Did Niu Bu Yan leave with him?
牛不言跟着他走了吗？
Niu Bu Yan was staying at Mr. Xu's house
牛不言住 在徐先生家里
I wonder if Mr. Xie took her up on that
不知道谢先生是否接受了她的建议？
What is your plan?
你的计划是什么？
Mr. Song
宋先生
I'm planning an ambush around Mr. Xie's house for two days with some guys
我正计划和一些人在谢先生家附近埋伏 两天
If the killer wanted to kill Niu Boyan
如果凶手想杀牛伯言
We cannot miss this opportunity
我们不能错过这个机会
How many men do you need?
你需要多少男人？
It's okay during the day
白天没问题
I need more for tonight
今晚我需要更多
Four sides of the house
房子的四个面
It can be guarded by five men each
每人可容纳五人看守
I'll give you 20 men
我给你20个人
quickly
迅速地
Go
去
Are they really pretending?
他们真的是在假装吗？
How did they travel?
他们如何旅行？
More than 30 km in half a day?
半天30多公里？
Lu San left
陆三离开
The righteous veil has been withdrawn from Yamin
正义的面纱已从 亚敏身上揭开
Thanks
谢谢
Did you hear him?
你听到他的声音了吗？
Judge Wei
魏法官
Please sit down
请坐下
Since she took office
自从她上任以来
I have never been involved in criminal justice
我从未参与 过刑事司法
I appreciate your dedication
我很欣赏你的奉献精神
You look different
你看起来不一样
ususally
通常
Today is different
今天不一样了
what is the difference?
有什么不同？
You'll know tomorrow
明天你就会知道
here
这里
Before I took office, I heard
在我上任之前，我听说
That Song Zhongqiu was the judge here
那个宋仲秋是这里的评委
I was happy
当时我很开心
I think I can learn poetry and calligraphy from you
我想我可以向你学习诗词 书法
Are you here
你在这里
To talk about poetry and calligraphy?
谈诗词书法？
I want to ask about a word
我想问一个词
Any one?
任何人？
Cruelty
残酷
You are very frank
你很坦诚
I used to work in DOE County
我曾经在 DOE 县工作
For 20 years
20年来
No one ever mentioned this
从来没有人提到过这一点
You don't want to talk about it?
你不想谈论它吗？
not really
并不真地
Others might think I don't want to talk about it
其他人可能认为 我不想谈论它
But I don't actually mind
但我其实并不介意
So I'm just ears
所以我只是耳朵
There are countless numbers of victims in this world
这个世界上有无数的受害者
But absolute justice never happened
但绝对的正义从未发生过
What do you mean by that?
你是什​​么意思？
You may not know
你可能不知道
There is not a single window in the prison
监狱里没有一扇窗户
You can't tell that day and night
你分不清白天和黑夜
But you can still feel
但你还是能感觉到
That days
那些日子
Pass
经过
How can you see it?
你怎么能看到它？
You can watch for your tortured chop
你可以留意你受尽折磨的印章
Slowly rot
慢慢腐烂
I was thinking
我刚在想
There was a threshold between life and death
生与死之间有一道门槛
Life on the side
生活在身边
And death on the other side
死亡就在另一边
Just a preliminary thing
只是初步的事情
But then I found out
但后来我发现
Death can be very slow
死亡可能会非常缓慢
People may die a little
人可能会死一点
one day
一天
The prison door is open
监狱的门是开着的
And someone will come and tell you
有人会来告诉你
That's your case
这就是你的情况
It was overturned
被推翻了
But by this time
但到了这个时候
You're half dead already
你已经半死不活了
Half of you have become a ghost
你的一半已经变成鬼了
And you can't go back to being a human
你无法变 回人类
You are half human
你是半个人
wild
荒野
Judge Wei
魏法官
Justice that comes too late
正义来得太迟
Not justice
不是正义
Sangang
九
what is wrong
怎么了
Are you disturbed by something?
你有什么事情打扰你吗？
permission
允许
You were right
你是对的
What happened?
发生了什么？
I believe
我相信
Our grievances
我们的委屈
Not from prison
不是从监狱出来的
I was known as a top talent
我被称为顶尖人才
Famous for your painting and calligraphy
以书画闻名
But I was afraid
但我很害怕
Your right hand cannot take the Registry now
你的右手 现在无法拿起注册表
Is this the biggest injustice to you?
这是对你最大的不公平吗？
When I got home
当我到家时
The court had overturned your case
法院推翻了你的案子
But no one believed that you were wronged
却没人相信 你受了委屈
They all spoke
他们都发言了
About the amount you spent
关于您花费的金额
Who did you nominate?
你提名了谁？
How did you use your prayers?
你如何使用你的祷告？
To avoid a lawsuit
为了避免诉讼
Mr. Song
宋先生
Isn't this unfair?
这不是不公平吗？
Is it harsher than a prison sentence?
比坐牢还重吗？
You had a good girlfriend
你有一个好女朋友
He studied with you from an early age
他从小就和你一起学习
You are prepared for exams together
你们一起准备考试
Close like brothers
亲密如兄弟
You cannot bear the punishment
你无法承受惩罚
and until
直到
He used his death to prove his innocence
他用自己的死 来证明自己的清白
Mr. Song
宋先生
Could it be the greatest injustice in your heart?
难道这就是你心中最大的不平吗？
in my opinion
在我看来
This is not the most unfair
这还不是最不公平的
You cannot live in peace
你无法平静地生活
Even if the court has cleared your name
即使法庭已经为你洗清了罪名
I restored your honor and gave you the high position
我恢复了你的荣誉 并给了你崇高的地位
Your right hand has become useless
你的右手已经没用了
People still think you were nominated
人们仍然认为你被提名了
Your dear friend died resentful
你亲爱的朋友含怨而死
However those who reported in court
然而那些在法庭上举报的人
Those who caused your disability
那些导致你残疾的人
Those who are busy in infighting
那些忙于内讧的人
And those who accuse you
还有那些指责你的人
By bribery
通过贿赂
None of them have ever
他们中没有一个人曾经
No punishment
没有惩罚
Mr. Song
宋先生
It's not just about injustice
这不仅仅是不公正的问题
You just don't know
你只是不知道
How do you take revenge?
你如何报仇？
I was constipated.
我便秘了。
My stool is hard like rocks.
我的凳子硬得像石头一样。
Sanjing.
Sanjing.
Sangang
九
It's okay if you don't want to tell me
如果你不想告诉我也没关系
However, you won't be alone
然而，你不会孤单
I believe
我相信
The reason you became a judge
你成为法官的原因
It is that you are a designer
就在于你是一名设计师
To solve every issue for justice
为正义解决每一个问题
I have been a judge for 12 years
我当法官12年了
I saw
我看见
Lots of pending issues
许多悬而未决的问题
This terrible
这太可怕了
20 years ago
20年前
Doe County has been hit by a lot of fire
多伊县遭受严重火灾
Have you heard of that?
你听说过吗？
So you were here for the fire 20 years ago
所以20年前你来这里 是为了火灾
I felt upset
我感到不安
I looked into it during my time on the run
我在逃亡期间研究过这个问题
It's almost over
快结束了
But my writing is clumsy
但我的文笔很蹩脚
I hide it in the box in my study
我把它藏在书房的盒子里
I do this to make myself happy
我这样做是为了让自己快乐
But after I finish writing
但当我写完之后
I hope you can review it
我希望你能评论一下
at that time
当时
Please give me your advice
请给我你的建议
Amol only
仅阿莫尔
You don't leave another case hanging
你不会让另一个案件悬而未决
What can I do for you?
我能为你做什么？
I'm in your serves
我为你服务
No hurry
不着急
you will know
你会知道
tomorrow
明天
Please
请
my friend
我的朋友
my lord
我的主
Any vacancies?
有职位空缺吗？
I am really sorry
真的对不起
Imperial scholar
进士
All rooms are booked for tonight
今晚所有房间都被预订了
Also book your rooms?
还订房间吗？
Yes
是的
He has three hostels
他拥有三间宿舍
He came with a lot of people
他带着很多人来
Sorry
对不起
You have a long time to come
你还有很长一段时间要来
There is another hostel
还有另一间宿舍
Take care, sir
保重，先生
Ma'am, I want two cakes
女士，我想要两个蛋糕
Good
好的
my lord
我的主
San is not enough?
桑还不够吗？
They outnumber us
他们的数量超过我们
Liu San can't monitor them alone
刘三一个人无法监视他们
If I'm not by your side
如果我不在你身边
I'm always worried
我总是很担心
I'm asking you to watch the most anxious person
我请你 关注最焦虑的人
But Chewie
但是楚伊
Do you mean it?
你是这个意思吗？
He went to Mr. Xie's house?
他去谢先生家了？
Didn't see this coming
没有看到这个的到来
How did he find that donkey?
他是怎么找到那头驴的？
Ko Sanqing is very planned
柯三清很有计划
I'm afraid he's setting a trap
我怕他设下陷阱
With Mr. Xie to take revenge on his master
与谢先生一起为师父报仇
As long as we don't act
只要我们不行动
What can they do?
他们能做什么？
Mr. Shiqi has Liu Shiqi by his side
Mr. Shiqi has Liu Shiqi by his side
Doesn't he fear us?
他就不怕我们吗？
Zhang Jie died
Zhang Jie died
permission
允许
Mr. Shiqi will keep Liu Shiqi by his side to protect himself
世奇先生会把柳世奇 留在身边保护自己
Judge Wei
魏法官
I feel like this is unsafe
我觉得这不安全
Is there any other way?
还有其他办法吗？
There is no other way
没有其他办法
I don't really have a choice
我真的别无选择
Judge Wei
魏法官
Without saving me
没有拯救我
I would die in prison
我会死在监狱里
I can risk my life
我可以冒生命危险
for you
为你
But I can't leave you in danger
但我不能让你处于危险之中
Where is the danger?
危险在哪里？
Are you afraid that I can't finish my policy?
你担心 我无法完成我的保单吗？
no
不
(interrupt check)
（中断检查）
(I am Wei Feng Shi, District Judge of Du County)
（我是杜县地方法官石伟峰）
(I am incompetent at work)
（我工作能力不行）
(Since taking office in Dou Province)
（窦省就任以来）
(I saw repeated killings) without evidence.
（我看到反复的杀戮） 没有证据。
(On the seventh day of October,)
（十月初七，）
(Cheng Yiqi, a distinguished doctor, came to confess on his own
（名医程亦奇 亲自前来表白
(He made his confession)
（他承认了）
(Based on his confession,)
（根据他的供述，）
(20 years ago, Lu Che) The owner of the Lu family
（20年前，陆彻） 陆家家主
(He forced him to poison his master to poison his master Lu Yuan Bao
（他逼他毒死他师父 毒死他师父陆元宝
(Lu Che set the fire and killed Lu Jinchen (Liu Yuanbao's brother and his family)
（陆彻放火杀死了陆金尘 （刘元宝的弟弟及其家人）
(He usurped his property)
（他侵占了他的财产）
(Lu Qi changed his name to Xue Qi)
(Lu Qi changed his name to Xue Qi)
(He has many accomplices)
（他有很多同伙）
(murder series in du county)
（杜县连环杀人案）
(Everything is done by his gang)
（一切都是他一帮人干的）
(It all started with Ling Wuji, Captain Ling)
（这一切都要 从凌无极、凌队长说起）
(Ling Wuji was one) of Xue Qi's partners
雪琪的搭档（凌无忌之一）
(He was blackmailing Xu Qi)
（他是在敲诈徐奇）
(since then)
（自那以后）
(Xie Qi began a series of killings for his secret. )
（谢启为了他的秘密开始了一系列的杀戮。 ）
Make your mark
发挥你的才能
(Testimony of Cheng Yiqi) (Cheng Yiqi claimed)
(Testimony of Cheng Yiqi) (Cheng Yiqi claimed)
(He feared he was killed)
（他担心自己会被杀）
(So ​​he chose to confess)
（所以？？？？？？他选择了坦白）
(to avoid death in prison)
（避免死在监狱里）
(Yawang Temple) (His confession seemed ridiculous)
（雅王寺） （他的忏悔显得很可笑）
(So ​​I thought he was crazy)
（所以？？？？？？我以为他疯了）
(She kept his confession) and led him away
（她保留了他的供词） 并把他带走了
(However, after three days)
（不过三天后）
(Zheng Yiqi was killed)
(Zheng Yiqi was killed)
(I felt terrified)
（我感到害怕）
(Such a person could actually be exposed to such a disease) (I realized the mistake I made)
（这样的人实际上可能会患上这样的疾病） （我意识到我犯了错误）
(Wrong Ghost Worship) (Later, Zhao Yuren was killed)
（错鬼崇拜） （后来赵玉仁被杀）
(A confession was also found at his house)
（在他家里还发现了一份口供）
(Zhao Yuren's confession) (Identified Xie Qi as the killer)
（赵玉仁供述） （指认谢奇为凶手）
(presumed killed)
（推测已被杀）
(before confession)
（表白前）
(This issue is huge)
（这个问题太大了）
(Xie Qi is an imperial scholar)
（谢启为翰林学士）
(I have no concrete evidence)
（我没有具体证据）
(So, I should report it first)
（所以，我应该先举报）
(And collect evidence secretly)
（并秘密收集证据）
Somebody
有人
drinker
饮酒者
Drink
喝
Drink more
多喝点
Let's go
我们走吧
Drink
喝
Ko Sangg
我的助理
Mr. Song is looking for you
宋先生正在找你
Why?
为什么？
He didn't tell me
他没有告诉我
Let's go
我们走吧
He just wants to see you
他只是想见你
my lord
我的主
Everything you said is the truth
你说的都是事实
I do not know anything
我什么都不知道
I didn't do anything, sir
我什么也没做，先生
You can leave now
你现在可以离开了
let him go
放了他
Yes
是的
my lord
我的主
Did you catch the real culprit?
你抓到真正的罪魁祸首了吗？
almost
几乎
very soon
很快
Thank you
谢谢
A few days ago when Niu Boyan left the city
前几天 牛伯言出城的时候
Unlike Zhang Jiechu who was hidden in his cart
不像张杰初 藏在车里
There was also a supervisor Leo, right?
还有一个主管 Leo吧？
Yes
是的
When I captured Zhang Jiechu
When I captured Zhang Jiechu
help
帮助
the person
此人
Who attacked Lan San using lime arts
是谁用石灰术袭击了蓝三
It was also Leo
这也是狮子座
Yes
是的
Liu San is watching Mr. Xie
刘三看着谢先生
The skilled men followed you to monitor Shui's residence
技术人员跟着你 监视水的住所
I called the fascia a while ago
不久前我给筋膜打过电话
There are only five couriers left in Yamen
衙门只剩下五个快递员了
Some of them were already drunk
有的人已经喝醉了
If Leo suddenly comes
如果狮子座突然来
To assassinate Judge Wei
刺杀魏法官
What will happen?
会发生什么？
Why would he kill Judge Wei?
他为什么要杀魏法官？
Because Judge Wee
因为黄法官
He is a serial killer
他是一个连环杀手
I drew it
我画的
With my left hand
用我的左手
It's not very lively but okay
不是很热闹但是还可以
This is Judge Wei
这是魏法官
Mr. Shi
Mr. Shi
permission
允许
This is the killer
这就是杀手
I showed it to Si Baozhou
我拿给司宝舟看
He said
他说
This was the customer who ordered the stone mill from
这是订购石磨机的顾客
Those who were stolen because of the monkey demon
那些因为猴妖而被偷走的人
this
这
It was the antique dealer who came to them
来找他们的是古董商
Could this be accurate?
这可能准确吗？
probably
大概
I painted nine pictures
我画了九张图
They are all servants and messengers in Yemen
他们都是 也门的仆人和使者
When the killer used the flying knife to deliver a message, I was sure it was him
当凶手用飞刀 传递信息时，我就确定是他了
The killer had an insider in Al-Yamin
凶手在亚明有一个知情人
So I gathered them together in the two days
所以我这两天把它们聚集在一起
I asked them one by one
我一一问他们
Seven of them could not prove
其中七人无法证明
Where were they?
他们在哪里？
I drew pictures for each of them
我为他们每个人都画了图
To let Si Baozhou identify him
为了让司宝舟认出他
But none of them were buyers
但他们都不是买家
I haven't drawn for a long time
我好久没画画了
In fact, it piqued my interest
事实上，它激起了我的兴趣
So I pulled two other people who had nothing to do with the case
于是我又拉了两个 与案子无关的人
Just for fun
只是为了好玩
But unexpectedly
但没想到的是
This is getting to be a lot of fun
这会变得很有趣
Only two pictures
只有两张图
Before I released Zhang Jizhou
在我释放张继洲之前
She submitted a special report to Judge Wei
她向魏法官提交了专题报告
Certainly enough
当然够了
Judge Wei and Mr. Shi
魏法官与石先生
Yamin left in civilian clothes very quickly
亚敏 很快就穿着便服离开了
What should we do now?
我们现在应该做什么？
I think Judge Wei found out
我想魏法官发现了
That Mr. Shweh left the district to confuse him
Shweh 先生离开该地区 是为了让他感到困惑
So he decided to go with him
于是决定跟他一起走
He asked Liuyi San to follow him
他让六一三跟着他
He left the door open
他没关门
Leave the door open?
让门开着吗？
Why?
为什么？
He wants that killer
他想要那个杀手
To come and kill him
来杀了他
So he set up a trap
于是他设下陷阱
To catch that killer
为了抓住那个杀手
Then extract a confession
然后提取口供
It's too much trouble
太麻烦了
If that killer kills him
如果那个杀手杀了他
He wouldn't need confession anymore
他不再需要忏悔
(I learned)
（我学会了）
(Xie Qi has many bandits)
（谢启土匪众多）
(And the famous thieves)
（还有著名的盗贼）
(A few days ago, the bandits sent a message with a flying knife)
（前几天，土匪发来消息 ，带着飞刀）
(to confuse people)
（迷惑人们）
(Yemen is under heavy guard)
（也门戒备森严）
(But they come and go as they please)
（但他们想来就来，想走就走）
(I'm afraid)
（我耽心）
(from getting hurt)
（免于受伤）
(So, I left this message)
（所以，我留下了这条消息）
(If you were really killed)
（如果你真的被杀了的话）
(The killer must be Xie Qi)
（凶手一定是谢启）
(I'm willing to trade my life)
（我愿意用我的生命来交换）
(to enforce laws)
（执行法律）
(and justice)
（和正义）
(This is what I'm after)
（这就是我所追求的）
(I don't regret it)
（我不后悔）
Judge Wei has a plan
魏法官有一个计划
Once Mr. Xie assassinates an official
一次谢先生刺杀官员
Regardless of his identity
不管他的身份如何
And his great wealth
还有他的巨额财富
It will be over
一切都会结束
He tried to die with Mr. Xie
他试图和谢先生一起死
Does he have to do that?
他必须这样做吗？
He is determined to get revenge
他决心报仇
He can do anything for that
为此他可以做任何事
If Judge Wei is the killer
如果魏法官是凶手
Captain Ling was killed by Hu
凌队长被胡杀了
He is your enemy
他是你的敌人
I'm going to Xie's house now
我现在去谢家
To bring them back
把他们带回来
Wait a minute
等一下
It will alert people
它会提醒人们
That's why you only brought me back
所以你才把我带回来
Mr. Song
宋先生
what do you want to do?
你想让我做什么？
Somebody
有人
Grab Choi
抢财
I took the note
我记下了笔记
On that sanctuary
在那圣地
When did you know that Judge Wei was the killer?
你什么时候知道 魏法官就是凶手的？
Before you do
在你做之前
But you were pretending
但你却在假装
Originally
起初
I didn't want to do anything
我什么都不想做
To watch it
观看它
If that killer comes tonight
如果今晚那个凶手来了
And he will succeed
他会成功
You will take revenge on your master
你将为你的主人报仇
I will take Judge Wei's decision
我会接受魏法官的决定
For evidence
供证据
To request the order from Nitai Yamin
向 Nitai Yamin 请求订单
To arrest Mr. Xie
逮捕谢先生
now
现在
We should call him Lu Che
我们应该叫他陆彻
I will also hold the New Boyan
我也会举办新博颜
So
所以
Revenge will end with the Lu family
陆家的复仇终将结束
What is your opinion
你有什么意见
Chewie, I ask you
楚伊，我问你
Seems fair
看起来公平
fair?
公平的？
but
但
do you know
你知道吗
What is true fairness?
什么是真正的公平？
permission
允许
I had a friend who died
我有一个朋友去世了
He committed suicide
他自杀了
But immediately after his death
但在他死后不久
The case was cancelled
案件被取消
So I wrote him a very long blessing
于是我给他写了很长的祝福
I wanted him to know
我想让他知道
That his name has been cleansed
他的名字已被洗净
It was a stupid day
这是愚蠢的一天
I thought it was him
我以为是他
It was going to rain
快要下雨了
I just waited in silence
我只是默默地等待
Waiting for him to tell me
等他告诉我
He can rest in peace
他可以安息了
And waiting for him to tell me
并等待他告诉我
That he could be reincarnated
他可以转世
I kept waiting until it became a shade
我一直等待，直到它变成阴影
But nothing happened
但什么也没发生
Not even a drop of rain
连一滴雨都没有
So I realized
所以我意识到
He died
他死了
He can see
他能看到
And I don't hear anything
我什么也没听到
And I wrote that wine
我写了那酒
Only for myself
只为我自己
I fooled myself with it
我用它欺骗了自己
Judge Wei has a 20-year-old grievance
魏法官 有20年冤屈
No matter what
无论
I have to keep him alive
我必须让他活下去
I need him to see those injustices
我需要他看到那些不公正的事情
It can be settled
是可以解决的
permission?
允许？
I will do justice
我会伸张正义
To Captain Ling
致凌队长
Judge Wei is a rank seven official
韦法官 是七品官员
Judge at a lower level
下级法官
The killer is the district judge
凶手是地区法官
Can you do justice?
你能伸张正义吗？
For Captain Ling?
为了凌队长？
I can
我可以
You should think about it
你应该考虑一下
If your plan with Mr. Xie is successful
如果你和谢先生的计划成功的话
What will you owe?
你会欠什么？
Can you pay for it?
你能付钱吗？
Judge Wei
魏法官
Mr. Song?
宋先生？
what's going on
这是怎么回事
This is urgent
这很紧急
please forgive me
请原谅我
What do you do?
你做什么工作？
how dare you!
你怎么敢！
His Majesty the Emperor appointed me
皇帝陛下任命我为
Fifth-level official
五级官员
The situation is urgent
情况紧急
Judge Wei
魏法官
I'm sorry about this
对此我很抱歉
permission
允许
Nothing I fear
我无所畏惧
Senseless killer
无意识的杀手
I do as he loves me
我做他爱我的事
If you get caught
如果你被抓住
We will not call a man
我们不会叫一个男人
to stop
停止
Please
请
You can kill me
你可以杀了我
But you can't insult me ​​like that
但你不能这样侮辱我？？？？？？
to speak
说话
Why did you kill Judge Wei?
为什么要杀魏法官？
Someone gave me 500 taels of silver
有人给了我五百两银子
from?
从？
I don't know
我不知道
my lord
我的主
I have to take him here for questioning
我得带他来这里问话
I'll go with you
我和你一起去
Mr. Song
宋先生
Judge Wei
魏法官
quickly
迅速地
why did you come here?
你为什么来这里？
The injustice is terrible
不公平是可怕的
your justice
你的正义
It can be done
可以办到
I envy you
我羡慕你
I know who you are
我知道你是谁
Why didn't you die?
你为什么没死？
I was supposed to die
我本来应该死的
But now I can't die
但现在我不能死
Justice must be done
正义必须得到伸张
You got justice for me
你为我伸张正义
And I will get justice for you
我会为你伸张正义
Sangang
九
What are you hiding from me?
你到底瞒着我什么？
I lied on you
我对你撒了谎
I found the note on the donkeys
我找到了驴子上的字条
Written here
写在这里
Judge Wei Ho Lu is with you
吕伟和法官与您同在
he did not die
他没有死
He's back for revenge
他回来报仇了
do you mean
你的意思是
Judge Wei is the killer?
魏法官就是凶手？
I can't deal with Judge Wei
我对付不了魏法官
So I found Mr. Shaw
于是我找到了肖先生
And tell him about it
并告诉他这件事
I wanted to at first
我一开始就想
to use it
使用它
To take revenge on my teacher
为老师报仇
So, you know
所以你知道
Something was going to happen tonight
今晚将会发生一些事情
So you intentionally shift our perspective?
所以你故意改变我们的观点？
This is my idea
这是我的想法
I was the one who killed Mr. Song
是我杀了宋先生
Mr. Song was killed
宋先生被杀
Captain Shea
谢伊船长
And other brothers
还有其他兄弟
I killed them all
我把他们都杀了
Sangang
九
Sangeng, don't cry anymore
三更，别再哭了
We have to think about what we should do next
我们必须考虑下一步应该做什么
I don't know
我不知道
I really don't know
我真的不知道
My teacher died
我的老师去世了
And Mr. Song died too
宋先生也死了
I don't know who I should ask
我不知道该问谁
do not do
不要做
This is it
就是这个
For Mr. Song and others
致宋先生等人
Sangig
香菜
I've thought about it carefully
我仔细考虑过
I found something
我发现了一些东西
What is the matter?
什么事？
Now, we are the ones making the decisions
现在，我们是做出决定的人
Whether Judge Wei
魏法官是否
Or Mr. Shawiya
或者Shawiya先生
They are all trapped
他们都被困住了
Neither of them can do anything to the other
他们谁也不能对对方做任何事
The key now is
现在关键是
He is the one we should help
他是我们应该帮助的人
We are so important?
我们有那么重要吗？
naturally
自然
from one side
从一侧
He's the killer we need to catch
他就是我们要抓获的凶手
Judge Wei killed five people
魏法官杀了五人
Including that killer
包括那个杀手
Six in total
一共六个
And kill your master
并杀死你的主人
on the other side
另一方面
He is Mr. Shaw
他就是肖先生
That is, Lu Che
也就是陆澈
He slaughtered the entire Lu family
他屠杀了整个陆家
He also killed Ms. Lin
他还杀了林女士
And Mr. Song
还有宋先生
They are both killers
他们都是杀手
Where is justice?
正义在哪里？
Sangang
九
Actually you know what to do
其实你知道该怎么做
But my teacher
但我的老师
Whenever I don't know
每当我不知道的时候
What do I do
我该怎么办
I will ask myself
我会问自己
What will my teacher do?
我的老师会做什么？
But this time
但这一次
I can't ask
我不能问
I can't ask what choice he will make
我无法问他会做出什么选择
Captain Ling had already made a decision
凌队长已经做出了决定
But he made a mistake
但他犯了一个错误
you are right
你是对的
Shichong
Shichong
Let's go
我们走吧
where?
在哪里？
I have an idea
我有个主意
But we have to act quickly
但我们必须迅速采取行动
It will be difficult when the day break is over
天亮后就很难了
Understood
明白了
I understood too
我也明白了
Let's go
我们走吧
Liu Shichi had done it
刘世池做到了
Are you ready?
你准备好了吗？
That man died?
那个人死了？
But Liu Shi Ke did not return
但刘世克却没有回来
Many people were killed in Yamin
雅敏多人被杀
He'll cause trouble if he comes back here
他再回来就会惹麻烦的
This is correct
这是对的
Fair enough
很公平
Let's go
我们走吧
where are you going?
你要去哪里？
Didn't Mr. Xie tell you?
谢先生没告诉你吗？
Tell me what?
告诉我什么？
After such a big accident
发生这么大的事故后
Is it okay to stay here?
留在这里可以吗？
I must hide
我必须隐藏
Mr. Shaw entrusted me
肖先生委托我
To accompany you out of town
陪你出城
To meet him
去见他
The city gates have not opened yet
城门还没有打开
So, that's why he asked me to accompany you
所以他才叫我 陪你
Let's leave now
我们现在就离开吧
What?
什么？
Want to take some people
想带一些人
To protect you along the way?
一路上保护你？
Forget it
忘了它
More people will draw attention
会引起更多人的关注
good
好的
I can't take out a lot of people
我不能带很多人出去
I'm not worried you'll play any tricks
我不担心 你会耍花招
Now, we're in the same boat
现在，我们在同一条船上
We are all in this together
我们荣辱与共
Mr. Ko
先生。糖
Did we take the wrong path?
我们是不是走错了路？
The eastern gate is there
东门在那里
We won't go there
我们不会去那里
where are we going?
我们去哪？
To the right
向右
Liu Shiqi failed
Liu Shiqi failed
Come back with us to Yamin for trial
跟我们一起回 亚敏受审吧
There is no evidence
没有证据
On what basis are you taking me?
你凭什么带走我？
For any reason?
出于任何原因？
Incitement of trouble
煽动制造麻烦
And resisting arrest
并拒捕
You...
你...
Go
去
You are an emperor
你是皇帝
Are your dishes still salty?
你的菜还咸吗？
Think about it carefully
仔细想想
think about it
想想看
What options are available to Lu Che now?
陆澈现在有什么选择？
Who else is besides him?
除了他之外还有谁？
It doesn't matter
没关系
You
你
No evidence
没有证据
He's right
他是对的
Then release him
然后放开他
Release him when it gets dark
天黑时放开他
you go
你去
Be careful on your way home
回家路上要小心
She doesn't end up like Zhang Jie
她最终没有像张杰那样
I am waiting
我在等待
How can I save my life?
我怎样才能挽救我的生命？
20 years ago
20年前
Lu Che killed the Lu family
陆彻杀了陆家
After 20 years
20年后
He started killing to avoid future problems
他开始杀人 是为了避免未来的问题
You are an accomplice in crime
你是犯罪的共犯
But you turned yourself in to testify
但你却自首作证
You won't die
你不会死
but
但
You will be in prison for years
你将在监狱里度过数年
Not possible
不可能
What's your idea?
你有什么想法？
Nothing about what happened 20 years ago
20年前发生的事根本就没有发生过
Lu Qi and I were servants of the Lu family
我和陆奇都是 陆家的下人
I saved him from the fire
我把他从火中救了出来
He owed me
他欠我的
We became close friends
我们成了亲密的朋友
A few days ago
几天之前
He almost lost his mind and started killing people
他几乎失去了理智 并开始杀人
I don't know why
我不知道为什么
I found out he was a murderer
我发现他是杀人犯
I convinced him to surrender
我说服他投降
But he booked me
但他给我订了
He tried to kill me several times
他多次试图杀了我
But he couldn't do it because I once saved his life
但他做不到， 因为我曾经救过他的命
I took the opportunity to escape
我趁机逃跑
When he left town
当他离开小镇时
This was reported to Yemen
此事已报告给也门
Your testimony does not stand up to scrutiny
你的证词经不起推敲
Lu Che will torture you
陆澈会折磨你的
I know he will
我知道他会
permission
允许
may be
或许
To bite you too
也来咬你
Well it's over
好了，结束了
Something extra
额外的东西
I can be the witness
我可以做证人
But how do you protect me?
但你要怎么保护我呢？
Who silenced him?
谁让他沉默了？
You will be safe before the case is closed
在案件结案之前您将是安全的
After closing
关闭后
I think you will definitely find a way
我想你一定会找到办法的
To get away
脱身
And
和
Thats all about it?
这就是全部吗？
Would you believe anything else I say?
你会相信我说的其他事情吗？
Okay, I'll listen to you
好的，我听你的
You will find out
你会发现
What happened 20 years ago
20年前发生了什么
The sectarian letter I was asked to write last night
昨晚我被要求写的宗派信
It was kitsch
这是媚俗的
And based on that
并以此为基础
You may not be able to defeat me
你或许无法打败我
If you go back on your words
如果你反悔的话
I can always find a way
我总能找到办法
When it's over
当一切结束的时候
I will kill myself as I promised you
我会按照我向你承诺的那样自杀
You planned to die with your enemy
你计划与你的敌人同归于尽
That's why we believe you half
这就是为什么我们一半相信你
Revenge is not easy
报仇并不容易
For both of us
为了我们俩
I'm not doing this for revenge
我这样做不是为了报复
Not for revenge?
不是为了报仇吗？
Captain Leng has been avenged
冷队长已经报仇了
You're doing it for Mr. Song
你这是为了宋先生
Mr. Song has no grudge with anyone
宋先生与任何人无仇
He just did his duty as a judge
他只是尽了法官的职责
I am only doing my duty as an advisor
我只是尽我作为顾问的职责
Give Way
泄露
Clear path
畅通无阻的道路
Here is the arrest warrant
这是逮捕令
We are here to catch Xue Qi
我们是来抓雪琪的
The others are unrelated
其他的都没有关系
Please step aside
请靠边站
Or you will be seen as a partner
否则你会被视为 合作伙伴
to retreat
撤退
(Prosperity) I am an imperial scholar
（繁荣） 我是一名御书生
This is not a memo from local Yamin
这不是本地亚民的备忘录
He is from Nitai Yamin
他来自尼泰亚敏
Your title has already been cancelled
您的头衔已被取消
You
你
here
这里
I'm here
我在这
It's been 20 years
已经20年了
I have some questions for you
我有一些问题想问你
Help yourself
帮助自己
Mr. Bey
贝先生
How did you survive?
你是怎么活下来的？
Who was that heavenly corpse?
那天尸是谁？
Do you remember Xiao Bo from Zhua Tower?
Do you remember Xiao Bo from Zhua Tower?
That corpse was Xiao Bao?
那具尸体就是小宝？
Was he at Lu's house at that time?
他当时在陆家吗？
at that time
当时
If only you knew Xiao Bo over there
要是你认识那边的小波就好了
Would you have saved him?
你会救他吗？
some thing
某物
Inescapable
不可避免的
I was sad for him
我为他感到难过
I was burning his paper money
我正在烧他的纸钱
permission
允许
I'm also sad for Lou
我也为卢感到难过
I burned paper for him every year
我每年都为他烧纸
But
但
At that time, Lu Che
那时的陆彻
It wouldn't have saved him
这并不能拯救他
Lu Che had no other way
陆澈也没有别的办法了
I know
我知道
I was originally called Xie
我本来叫谢
I am not Lu Che
我不是陆彻
I'm not a Loyo Boutique
我不是Loyo精品店
You...
你...
Are you not a Leo?
你不是狮子座吗？
Do you still remember Xiao Bao?
你还记得小宝吗？
Xiao Bo
Xiao Bo
Mr. Lu
先生。太阳
Xiao Bao
Xiao Bao
Are you Xiao Bao?
你是小宝吗？
What interest?
什么兴趣？
- It's already been burned - Lu Che
- 已经被烧掉了 - 陆澈
However
然而
I still need to see it
我还需要看看
He must die
他必须死
One, two, three, four, five, six, seven, eight
一、二、三、四、 五、六、七、八
Nine, ten, 11, twelve
九、十、十一、十二
Thirteen, fourteen
十三、十四
I wouldn't dare start a fire
我不敢生火
I can't eat it
我不能吃它
But you ate it
但你吃了它
(after a year)
（一年后）
Mr. Lu
先生。太阳
I know what's going on
我知道发生了什么事
I learned to read
我学会了读书
Lu Zhong wrote
Lu Zhong wrote
Everything
一切
Guess what?
你猜怎么了？
It wasn't a mutation
这不是突变
Mr. Lu
先生。太阳
Lu Che did a lot of bad things
陆彻做了很多坏事
And bad people help him
坏人帮助他
Mr. Lu
先生。太阳
in this world
在这世上
There are many good people like you
像你这样的好人还有很多
But all I see are good people...
但我看到的都是好人...
Mr. Lu
先生。太阳
I took some gold
我拿了一些金子
Engraving from Confucius Analykat
孔子 Analykat 的雕刻
Made of gold
由黄金制成
I saw a sentence in it
我看到里面有一句话
Some people hurt others themselves
有些人自己伤害了别人
While some hurt themselves to others
虽然有些人伤害了自己也伤害了别人
Mr. Lu
先生。太阳
You died to save me
你为救我而死
You hurt yourself for someone else
你为了别人伤害了自己
Since I took your gold
自从我拿走了你的金子
I can't take it for nothing
我不能白白接受
Mr. Lu
先生。太阳
I swear to you
我向你发誓
I will correct
我会改正的
I can not
我不能
permission
允许
What will you tell me?
你会告诉我什么？
for me?
为我？
You know that
你懂的
Just one phrase is most appropriate
一句话最合适
Who wins against the sky?
谁能胜天？
It would be hopeless
那就无望了
Whoever mediates against heaven
凡是与天为敌的人
It's ridiculous
太荒谬了
in my life
在我生命中
I never asked heaven for anything
我从未向天堂祈求过什么
but now
但现在
Heaven wants to punish me
上天要惩罚我
this is the way
就是这样
The sky is unbelievable
天空令人难以置信
Yes in deed
确实是的
Oh
哦
I have another question
我有另一个问题
How did you know about these things?
你是怎么知道这些事情的？
How did you know about Mr. Wang?
你是怎么知道王先生的？
Dr. Cheng
Dr. Cheng
And Mr. Chow?
周先生呢？
You don't want to say that
你不想这么说
In front of them?
在他们面前？
It seems
它似乎
Heaven doesn't just punish me
上天不仅惩罚我
It also makes me die
也让我死去活来
Without knowing the truth
在不知道真相的情况下
Good
好的
I'll tell you that
我会告诉你
Understood
明白了
As you know
如你所知
She was born with a bad fate
她生来就有不幸的命运
I just want to change my destiny
我只想改变我的命运
Judge Wei
魏法官
Receive a doctor
接待医生
Have you tasted?
你尝过吗？
Crispy pastries?
脆皮糕点？
It's really
是真的
Tasty
可口
(Make food superior)
（让食物更优质）
Sorry
对不起
When I was cleaning Mr. Song's things
当我清理宋先生的东西时
I found this
我找到了这个
Written on it: "For the sake of glory"
上面写着：“为了荣耀”
I asked everywhere
我到处询问
I probably found it for you
我可能已经为你找到了
Mr. Song?
宋先生？
Early flower fairy
早花仙子
It's a poem?
这是一首诗？
(In a far away land,)
（在遥远的地方，）
(There is a fairy for the flower)
（有花有仙）
(fun tree fantasy plants)
（有趣的树幻想植物）
(with falling peat)
（有掉落的泥炭）
(The fairy starts dancing gently)
（仙女开始轻轻跳舞）
(Low flowers are the reward)
（低花是奖励）
(smoke and singing)
（抽烟和唱歌）
(She lives in peace)
（她过着平静的生活）
"Some people don't like flowers"
“有些人不喜欢花”
"The wind blows the flowers away."
“风把花吹走了。”
(Precious flowers are in favor) )
（名贵鲜花优先） ）
(At a time when you suffer the world's contempt)
（当你遭受全世界的蔑视时）
(If you compare the two)
（如果比较两者的话）
(People will think I'm crazy)
（人们会认为我疯了）
(compared to these people)
（与这些人相比）
(I'd rather be crazy)
（我宁愿疯了）
(I am wary of trap flowers)
（我对陷阱花很警惕）
(A link will be formed)
（将形成一个链接）
(millions of years later)
（数百万年后）
(I often sit under the flowers)
（我经常坐在花下）
(Even if I die, I will sleep)
（就算死了我也会睡觉）
(under the flowers)
（花下）
(No rank in punishment)
（处罚不分等级）
♪ In the middle of the bone and to the side of the blade ♪
??? 在骨头的中间 和刀片的侧面？？？
♪ There's something sweet and sticky ♪
??? 有东西又甜又粘？？？
♪ Living in ancient times ♪
??? 生活在古代？？？
♪ Some crying and some sleeping ♪
??? 有的在哭，有的在睡觉？？？
♪ Rich Offerings Sacrificial Services Are Offered ♪
??? 丰富的祭品 提供祭祀服务???
♪ There are barren blocks with flies stream around ♪
??? 有荒芜的街区 ，周围苍蝇成群？？？
♪ Ancient remote road and thriving cities ♪
??? 古老偏僻的道路 和繁华的城市？？？
♪ Wild fires never stop withering and thriving ♪
??? 野火永不停歇 ，又永不停息？？？
♪ A few plumes of smoke are freezing ♪
??? 几缕烟雾结冰了？？？
♪ You're making a wish ♪
??? 你许愿了？？？
♪ Empty promises and miserable stories ♪
??? 空洞的承诺和悲惨的故事？？？
♪ Appear without a trace ♪
??? 出现无影无踪？？？
♪ Offers are filled with services offered for sacrifice ♪
??? 优惠 充满了为牺牲而提供的服务？？？
♪ There are barren blocks with flies stream around ♪
??? 有荒芜的街区 ，周围苍蝇成群？？？
♪ Ancient remote road and thriving cities ♪
??? 古老偏僻的道路 和繁华的城市？？？
♪ Wild fires never stop and ♪
??? 野火永远不会停止 ，？？？